

James Robinson

Senior Full Stack Engineer

™ robinson.james0427@gmail.com

2515 Rose Way, Santa Clara, CA 95051

https://github.com/minionhub

Summary

Bringing more than 8 years of experience leading website design projects, including gathering user requirements, producing code, creating mockups and enhancing designs. Focused on creating clean, robust code with exceptional security. Achieves compatibility targets while meeting and exceeding customer demands.

Skills

Frontend

ReactJS, AngularJS, VueJS, React Native, NextJS, NuxtJS

Content Management System

WordPress, Shopify, Strapi

Database Management Systems

MySQL, MongoDB, SQL Server

Backend

NodeJS, ExpressJS, Laravel, PHP, Java, Python, RESTful API, Webpack

Version Control Tools

Git(Github, Gitlab), SVN

DevOps

AWS, Docker, Kubernetes

Professional Experience

Trustle, Senior Full Stack Engineer

Jul 2020 - Mar 2023

Walnut Creek, United States

Led a team of 5 developers in delivering several high-visibility projects, including large-scale applications using Next.js, AngularJS, Nuxt.js, Node/ExpressJS, Laravel, MySQL, and MongoDB from scratch resulting in a 20% increase in application productivity.

Andela, Senior Full Stack Engineer

Jul 2017 – Jun 2020

New York, United States

Developed and maintained e-commerce & healthcare products using React, NodeJS, MySQL, and MongoDB.

Worked in Agile methodologies for development to deliver better applications and used Jira and Git as version control and tracking units.

DevMynd, Software Developer

Jul 2015 - Jun 2017

San Francisco, United States

Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, and JSON coding and coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery languages. Provided front-end website development using WordPress, Shopify, and other editing software.

Education

Santa Clara University, Bachelor of Computer Science

Apr 2011 – May 2015

Santa Clara, United States